<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dustan Kasten</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/</link><description>Recent content on Dustan Kasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://iamdustan.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Books of 2020</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/04/books-of-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/04/books-of-2020/</guid><description>Catching up on posting my annual reading lists.
The List # Book Author Completed The Personal MBA Josh Kaufman February 9 The Last Wish Andrzej Sapkowski February 16 Making Work Visible Dominica DeGrandis February 21 Managing Humans Michael Lopp March 7 Managing Up Mary Abbajay March 14 Becoming Supernatural Dr. Joe Dispenza March 22 Leviathan Wakes James S.A.Corey April 5 Calibans War James S.A.Corey April 13 Hyperion Dan Simmons May 14 How to be an Antiracist Ibram X.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2019</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/03/books-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/03/books-of-2019/</guid><description>Catching up on posting my annual reading lists.
The List</description></item><item><title>Books of 2018</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2020/02/04/books-of-2018/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2020/02/04/books-of-2018/</guid><description>I’m posting this over a year late because I quit all forms of internet interactions. I’m not committing, but I’m thinking about writing to formulate my thoughts again so just pushing this up for posterity.
The List I find it interesting to review what I gravitate towards after the fact to discover where my interests lie. Standout books for this year that I have added to my recommended reading list are as follows:</description></item><item><title>Books of 2017</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/07/books-of-2017/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/07/books-of-2017/</guid><description>The List</description></item><item><title>A Year Without Twitter</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/03/a-year-without-twitter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/03/a-year-without-twitter/</guid><description>Two days ago I have been off of Twitter for a year. Life has been really good without it, but I also miss everyone in the React community whose ongoing relationship was primarily based around communication on Twitter.
So I ask&amp;hellip;do I come back? Or do I carry on with my life which has been really beautiful without the world-always-burning-down ethos of Twitter.</description></item><item><title>Transforming Interaction Design</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2017/03/14/transforming-interaction-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2017/03/14/transforming-interaction-design/</guid><description>Today is the day that a new chapter has begun. I am joining the wickedly sharp team at Webflow in the pursuit of transforming interaction design and product development!
To explain why I am so excited about Webflow I want to share a short story. I recently sat down with my friend Rob Luke to see what he’s working on at Passport. I was excited about what Passport is building and the caliber of what Rob was creating, but what really struck me was the immense frustration I felt regarding the process of product development.</description></item><item><title>Using Ocapic on OSX with ReasonML</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2017/02/21/using-ocapic-on-osx-with-reasonml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2017/02/21/using-ocapic-on-osx-with-reasonml/</guid><description>This is just some random documentation for myself in the future or the two other people on the planet who want to mess around with Ocapic on OSX while using Reason instead of Ocaml.
First you need to install all the things, then you need to write your souce code. If all you need is the magic incantion at the end with no explanations:
$ ocapic \ [ &amp;lt;pic&amp;gt; ] \ [ OCAMLC_OPTS ] \ [ OPTIONS ] \ -pp &amp;#34;refmt -parse re -print ml&amp;#34; &amp;lt;source.</description></item><item><title>On Almost Starting A Company</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2017/02/20/on-almost-starting-a-company/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2017/02/20/on-almost-starting-a-company/</guid><description>Who knew funemployment could be so busy! I haven’t written much here or contributed much to open source. I have done a pretty decent job on the other goals from my intentions, though.
I’m fairly confident in who I want to work for next, so I decided to take advantage of this time at taking a swing at starting a company. A couple friends and I spent the past couple weeks working extremely hard at putting a coworking space together.</description></item><item><title>Future</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2017/01/26/future/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2017/01/26/future/</guid><description>If you missed it yesterday I am now “funemployed” and am going to take full advantage of this period.
I will write more. I will connect with people more. I will contribute to open source more. I will learn more. I will smile more. I will have fun with my wife and kids more. I will give back more.
I’ve been thinking about what I want to be doing for a while now.</description></item><item><title>January</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2017/01/25/january/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2017/01/25/january/</guid><description>Yesterday, the 24th of January, was a rather shoddy day for many Directors at Walmart Labs. They had to spend the day laying off a couple hundred of the most productive, passionate, caring, and intelligent individuals I have had the privilege to work with. Oh, me too.
I woke up today quite excited. I’m not certain what is next yet, but I know it is going to be awesome. I am excited and optimistic about the future.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2016</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/12/28/books-of-2016/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/12/28/books-of-2016/</guid><description>Welp, it appears I have fallen off the reading list since having two kids. I did manage to sneak 12 books in yet this past year, but with a bit more fiction than years past. Apparently as I’ve entered 30 I appreciate entertainment just as much (or more than) learning. :)
The List</description></item><item><title>reinstall: a better `daggumnpm`</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/05/11/reinstall-a-better-daggumnpm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/05/11/reinstall-a-better-daggumnpm/</guid><description>daggumnpm, while fun, had a few rough edges. My workflow often involves running daggumnpm in a tmux session and working on something else while npm does it’s thing. When everything works this is great because I hear the friendly “Greetings, Dustan Kasten&amp;hellip;” message when the install completes. However, when npm install fails I completely forget about that process for entirely too long.
Whilst this could still be done with a single line bash alias, I’ve opted to use a more verbose implementation in the following little function reinstall.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2015</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/05/10/books-of-2015/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/05/10/books-of-2015/</guid><description>2016 was not “the Year of the Book” for me. Instead I moved into a new house, changed companies, and my wife and I had had our second child.
I also switched to Team Android, whilst my reading list was on my old iPhone, hence the reading list post in May.
The List Highlights I would recommend Engage the Fox, The Worthing Saga, The (Honest) Truth About Dishonesty, and The Music of the Primes for all audiences.</description></item><item><title>React Devtools-Renderer Integration</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/19/react-devtools-renderer-integration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/19/react-devtools-renderer-integration/</guid><description>Integrating React Hardware with the React DevTools was a goal from the first day of the project. As mentioned in my previous article on creating a renderer, I consider interoperability with the existing ecosystem to be of utmost importance.
This mission was accomplished this past weekend with some helpful guidance from @matthewwithanm. This article will begin with a few incorrect assumptions I had about how React, React Native and the DevTools interacted and end with a couple guidelines to writing your own renderer that can interoperate with the React DevTools.</description></item><item><title>daggumnpm: a friendly bash utility</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/18/daggumnpm-a-friendly-bash-utility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/18/daggumnpm-a-friendly-bash-utility/</guid><description>Update: there is an updated version of this at /2016/05/11/reinstall-daggumnpm/
No matter what version of npm you use, you likely have had to destroy your node_modules folder and do a clean npm install to debug some issue. This likely isn’t exclusive to npm either, but any package manager. Regardless, here’s a quick friendly bash script to reinstall your node_modules fresh, let you know when it’s done, and automatically run the previous command.</description></item><item><title>An Experiment with React, My Voice, and Hardware.</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/14/an-experiment-with-react-my-voice-and-hardware./</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/14/an-experiment-with-react-my-voice-and-hardware./</guid><description>I’ve been playing with creating a React renderer for hardware off and on over the past year. If you follow me on Twitter you may have seen that a milestone was reached two days ago when React Hardware and the React Devtools became friends.
I’ve been looking for a reason to play with the SpeechRecognition API. Chrome implemented the API a year or so ago and Firefox has support coming quickly.</description></item><item><title>React Custom Renderers</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/01/18/react-custom-renderers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/01/18/react-custom-renderers/</guid><description>You’re considering building a custom renderer for React and are wondering where to start and what to do? Welcome (to the land of dragons)! Just kidding, it’s not that bad—just undocumented and not officially supported. ¯\_(ツ)_/¯
This article is intended to be a high level view of the developer experience a renderer should aim to provide based on my experience with React, writing a renderer, and exploring other custom renderers. Note that this is not a guide on how to write a renderer.</description></item><item><title>React Hardware</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2015/12/16/react-hardware/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2015/12/16/react-hardware/</guid><description>React is proving that its component-driven architecture and abstractions hold up beyond browser-based user interfaces. React Native is bringing React’s authoring and architectural style to iOS and Android. Guillaume Plique has written a react-blessed renderer for terminal-based UIs. Netflix has written React bindings for their proprietary Gibbon rendering engine (React Conf 2015 talk). I’ve been writing a renderer for the Firmata protocol so that you can manipulate the real world with React.</description></item><item><title>The End of a Chapter</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2015/08/11/the-end-of-a-chapter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2015/08/11/the-end-of-a-chapter/</guid><description>This week marks the end of the best chapter of my career. The past four years at Skookum have without question changed my life. I came in knowing hardly a thing and today am a mostly competent developer. At Skookum I have worked alongside some of the smartest people I have ever met.
I’m very proud of what we’ve been able to accomplish over the past few years. We’ve shipped such a vast array of projects with such a diverse set of technologies.</description></item><item><title>How to choose a second language</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2015/04/17/how-to-choose-a-second-language/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2015/04/17/how-to-choose-a-second-language/</guid><description>So you’ve been programming for a while now and you want to explore what other languages are there. How do you choose?
Do you choose based on how you think you might get a job? Or do you choose where all the “excitement” is?
My advice? Find something that will change the way you think about programming.
Most likely you’ve been writing in some form of object-oriented language. That’s great. It’s what the vast majority of professional software developers author in.</description></item><item><title>Exploring CSS ASTs</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2015/04/08/exploring-css-asts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2015/04/08/exploring-css-asts/</guid><description>My greatest programming joys over the past few months have been whenever I get the opportunity to programmatically manipulate the code itself. Ever since transforming a number of projects containing 100s of modules from AMD to Common.js, it&amp;rsquo;s been stewing in my mind.
Though that was JavaScript. Let’s consider CSS for a bit. Professional experience and the wisdom of others has shown me repeatedly that CSS as a language has many footguns.</description></item><item><title>JSX. The Cognitive Hack</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2015/02/13/jsx.-the-cognitive-hack/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2015/02/13/jsx.-the-cognitive-hack/</guid><description>This short article is intended to convince the JSX holdouts a little bit more on why HTML in your JavaScript through JSX is a great idea.
For years we’ve been taught—and in turn echoed the belief—that HTML is our structure and JS is our behavior layer. HTML should only go in *.html files. Now I am certain there are some historical reasons for this, many of which are likely still relevant if you work in a DOM-as-source-of-truth world.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2014</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2015/01/23/books-of-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2015/01/23/books-of-2014/</guid><description>2014 was my year off from reading. Well, I read the Game of Thrones series. Now I sit here waiting for George R.R. Martin to finish the Winds of Winter so I can move on with my life for a month before waiting another 7 years for the 7th installation in the series. But alas, here is the list:
The List</description></item><item><title>Learning ClojureScript. For JavaScript Developers</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2014/09/02/learning-clojurescript.-for-javascript-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2014/09/02/learning-clojurescript.-for-javascript-developers/</guid><description>I’ve wanted to add a functional language to my knowledge belt for quite some time now. If you check out my 2013 reading list you may have noticed a Haskell book in there. Haskell was my introduction to thinking without state, but rather with immutable data structures and the syntax was so entirely different from what I was used to with JavaScript that I could not merely port my knowledge for how to solve a problem over in most situations.</description></item><item><title>Flexbox your buttons.</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2014/07/28/flexbox-your-buttons./</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2014/07/28/flexbox-your-buttons./</guid><description>There are certain properties that are not consistently applied across elements. If you’ve ever tried to style a &amp;lt;select /&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;file&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; element you have experienced this.
This doesn’t apply only to the visual styles we were pained by in the past, but also by layout properties such as display: block;.
I am working on a Phonegap project these days so I have a rather narrow range of rendering engines to support.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2013</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2014/01/09/books-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2014/01/09/books-of-2013/</guid><description>After accidentally reading 42 books in 2012, I had quietly set myself the goal of reaching 52 books in 2013. With a last minute book off of Lean Pub I pulled it off with 1 minute 12 seconds to spare.
The List Highlights There are a few stand out books from this list. First and foremost, Thinking Fast and Slow by Daniel Kahneman is a great book. I am fascinated by how the human mind works and this was my grand introduction to psychology.</description></item><item><title>CSSOM Smooth Scrolling</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2013/08/21/cssom-smooth-scrolling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2013/08/21/cssom-smooth-scrolling/</guid><description>Update: demo and documentation site: iamdustan.com/smoothscroll/
Coming soon to a browser near you Paul Irish recently shared on Google+ that the CSSWG has standardized smooth scrolling on behalf of web developers everywhere. This means no more jQuery or other such javascript to simply scroll to an element.
In the future you’ll be able to declare smooth scrolling in your css with body { scroll-behavior: smooth } or programmatically by using window.</description></item><item><title>Learning List</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2013/08/20/learning-list/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2013/08/20/learning-list/</guid><description>Just an arbitrary list of things I am currently in the process of exploring and learning or want to someday.
3D Programming (WebGL) Linear Algebra Enough C++ to land a commit in any browser engine TypeScript or Dart How human’s make decisions. Psychology/sociology. Game development Haskell Node.js Ruby (maybe Rails) Machine Learning</description></item><item><title>Browser Stories.</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2013/06/20/browser-stories./</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2013/06/20/browser-stories./</guid><description>There has always been something about Microsoft’s copy that bothers me. From their marketing copy on the IE download page, to their IE developer blog. I never quite could quite tell why.
Was it the arrogant tone with pleaful text shouting, “Look! We’re faster than Chrome with these benchmarks we wrote!”?
Was it the constant digs at other browser vendors in the midst of an otherwise sensible post?
No, no. Neither of these were the core of my discomfort.</description></item><item><title>Why I wake up.</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2013/03/18/why-i-wake-up./</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2013/03/18/why-i-wake-up./</guid><description>To help people. Quite simple.
I help companies streamline their company through business technology. I help companies improve their products through a better user experience. I help humans by assisting companies in scaling their technology product to the point of creating new jobs. I help humans by educating my fellow web developers to do the same. What I do matters. What you do matters, too.</description></item><item><title>Forks and Journeys.</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2013/02/17/forks-and-journeys./</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2013/02/17/forks-and-journeys./</guid><description>Who and where you are today is the cumultive effect of a lifetime of decisions. Actions. Reactions. Five years ago if you would’ve asked me what I would be doing for a living one year hence I would’ve had no clear answer for you. Yet, fate had it that I would be beginning my journey into web development.
Fast forward three years and you will find me working at JR Motorsports doing web design and front-end development, albeit at a rather mediocre level.</description></item><item><title>On Being Humbled.</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2013/01/31/on-being-humbled./</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2013/01/31/on-being-humbled./</guid><description>This is a story of a junior football player, and a rather delusional one at that. This boy had gotten a copy of Madden the year prior and had a growing interest in the sport because of it. After a year of Madden and the Sunday Ticket, he had amassed quite the knowledge base of the game of football.
He decided to take this knowledge and go to the next level and signed up at the local parks and rec.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2012</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2013/01/16/books-of-2012/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2013/01/16/books-of-2012/</guid><description>In 2012, my voracious appetite for reading and learning had reached new heights. Without setting any direct goals for reading, I began the year consuming book upon book upon book and kept a running record of what I had read so at year’s end I could look back on it all and see what I had discovered.
I inadvertently almost averaged a book a week and ended the year with 42.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://iamdustan.com/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/now/</guid><description>About this website I haven’t published in a few years. Mostly because I last updated this site on a pre-1.0 version of Gatsby that Kyle Matthews and I put together in 15 minutes during a React Conf session.
I expect this to continue to be a public location for random notes, thoughts, and ideas. Those will likely be shallow entries across music, engineering management, software engineering, visual development, neovim, and Obsidian.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/projects/</guid><description> Directory of Custom React Renderers React Hardware Tiny React Renderer Yellowbox React CSS SmoothScroll polyfill</description></item></channel></rss>