<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Work on Dustan Kasten</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/tags/work/</link><description>Recent content in Work on Dustan Kasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://iamdustan.com/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transforming Interaction Design</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2017/03/14/transforming-interaction-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2017/03/14/transforming-interaction-design/</guid><description>Today is the day that a new chapter has begun. I am joining the wickedly sharp team at Webflow in the pursuit of transforming interaction design and product development!
To explain why I am so excited about Webflow I want to share a short story. I recently sat down with my friend Rob Luke to see what he’s working on at Passport. I was excited about what Passport is building and the caliber of what Rob was creating, but what really struck me was the immense frustration I felt regarding the process of product development.</description></item><item><title>On Almost Starting A Company</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2017/02/20/on-almost-starting-a-company/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2017/02/20/on-almost-starting-a-company/</guid><description>Who knew funemployment could be so busy! I haven’t written much here or contributed much to open source. I have done a pretty decent job on the other goals from my intentions, though.
I’m fairly confident in who I want to work for next, so I decided to take advantage of this time at taking a swing at starting a company. A couple friends and I spent the past couple weeks working extremely hard at putting a coworking space together.</description></item><item><title>Future</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2017/01/26/future/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2017/01/26/future/</guid><description>If you missed it yesterday I am now “funemployed” and am going to take full advantage of this period.
I will write more. I will connect with people more. I will contribute to open source more. I will learn more. I will smile more. I will have fun with my wife and kids more. I will give back more.
I’ve been thinking about what I want to be doing for a while now.</description></item><item><title>January</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2017/01/25/january/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2017/01/25/january/</guid><description>Yesterday, the 24th of January, was a rather shoddy day for many Directors at Walmart Labs. They had to spend the day laying off a couple hundred of the most productive, passionate, caring, and intelligent individuals I have had the privilege to work with. Oh, me too.
I woke up today quite excited. I’m not certain what is next yet, but I know it is going to be awesome. I am excited and optimistic about the future.</description></item><item><title>The End of a Chapter</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2015/08/11/the-end-of-a-chapter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2015/08/11/the-end-of-a-chapter/</guid><description>This week marks the end of the best chapter of my career. The past four years at Skookum have without question changed my life. I came in knowing hardly a thing and today am a mostly competent developer. At Skookum I have worked alongside some of the smartest people I have ever met.
I’m very proud of what we’ve been able to accomplish over the past few years. We’ve shipped such a vast array of projects with such a diverse set of technologies.</description></item></channel></rss>