<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>React-Hardware on Dustan Kasten</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/tags/react-hardware/</link><description>Recent content in React-Hardware on Dustan Kasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://iamdustan.com/tags/react-hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>React Devtools-Renderer Integration</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/19/react-devtools-renderer-integration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/19/react-devtools-renderer-integration/</guid><description>Integrating React Hardware with the React DevTools was a goal from the first day of the project. As mentioned in my previous article on creating a renderer, I consider interoperability with the existing ecosystem to be of utmost importance.
This mission was accomplished this past weekend with some helpful guidance from @matthewwithanm. This article will begin with a few incorrect assumptions I had about how React, React Native and the DevTools interacted and end with a couple guidelines to writing your own renderer that can interoperate with the React DevTools.</description></item><item><title>An Experiment with React, My Voice, and Hardware.</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/14/an-experiment-with-react-my-voice-and-hardware./</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/02/14/an-experiment-with-react-my-voice-and-hardware./</guid><description>I’ve been playing with creating a React renderer for hardware off and on over the past year. If you follow me on Twitter you may have seen that a milestone was reached two days ago when React Hardware and the React Devtools became friends.
I’ve been looking for a reason to play with the SpeechRecognition API. Chrome implemented the API a year or so ago and Firefox has support coming quickly.</description></item></channel></rss>