<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reading List on Dustan Kasten</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/tags/reading-list/</link><description>Recent content in Reading List on Dustan Kasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://iamdustan.com/tags/reading-list/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Books of 2021</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2022/02/15/books-of-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2022/02/15/books-of-2021/</guid><description>Catching up on posting my annual reading lists.
The List # Book Author Completed Empowered Josh Bernoff, Ted Shadler January 2 Organisational structure and Elliot Jaques&amp;#39; stratified systems theory (white paper) Schalk Willem Grobler January 2 An Elegant Puzzle Will Larson January 5 Don&amp;#39;t Think of an Elephant George Lakoff January 9 On Bullshit Harry Frankfurt January 12 The Flame Leonard Cohen January 14 Inspired Marty Cagan January 18 Talking to Strangers Malcolm Gladwell January 19 Letters to a Young Poet Rainer Maria Rilke January 24 Just Mercy Bryan Stevenson January 24 Bird by Bird Anne Lamott February 3 Work Rules!</description></item><item><title>Books of 2020</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/04/books-of-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/04/books-of-2020/</guid><description>Catching up on posting my annual reading lists.
The List # Book Author Completed The Personal MBA Josh Kaufman February 9 The Last Wish Andrzej Sapkowski February 16 Making Work Visible Dominica DeGrandis February 21 Managing Humans Michael Lopp March 7 Managing Up Mary Abbajay March 14 Becoming Supernatural Dr. Joe Dispenza March 22 Leviathan Wakes James S.A.Corey April 5 Calibans War James S.A.Corey April 13 Hyperion Dan Simmons May 14 How to be an Antiracist Ibram X.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2019</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/03/books-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/03/books-of-2019/</guid><description>Catching up on posting my annual reading lists.
The List # Book Author Completed The Eye of the World Robert Jordan January 3 Between the World and Me Ta-Nahisi Coates January 4 The Great Hunt Robert Jordan February 5 The Dragon Reborn Robert Jordan February 5 A Time to Break Silence Martin Luther King, Jr. February 11 The Shadow Rising Robert Jordan March 3 The Fires of Heaven Robert Jordan March 24 Lord of Chaos Robert Jordan April 26 A Crown of Swords Robert Jordan May 13 The Path of Daggers Robert Jordan May 21 New Spring Robert Jordan June 4 Winters Heart Robert Jordan July 8 The Sun Does Shine Anthony Ray Hinton July 31 Crossroads of Twilight Robert Jordan August 23 Meditations Marcus Aurelius September 5 What is the Bible?</description></item><item><title>Books of 2018</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2020/02/04/books-of-2018/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2020/02/04/books-of-2018/</guid><description>I’m posting this over a year late because I quit all forms of internet interactions. I’m not committing, but I’m thinking about writing to formulate my thoughts again so just pushing this up for posterity.
The List # Book Author Completed Data Oriented Design Rechard Fabian February 5 The New Jim Crow Michelle Alexander May 6 Crucial Conversations Al Switzler, Joseph Grenny, and Ron McMillan June 5 The Bully Pulpit Doris Kearns Goodwin June 10 Astrophysics for People in a Hurry Neil deGrasse Tyson June 16 The Sixth Extinction Elizabeth Kolbert June 20 Agent Garbo Stephan Talty June 21 Moonwalking With Einstein Josh Foer June 25 The Three-Body Problem Cixin Liu June 28 The Dark Forest Cixin Liu July 2 Death’s End Cixin Liu July 20 A Hope More Powerful Than The Sea Melissa Flemming October 4 The Nature of Software Development Ron Jeffries October 8 The Moon is a Harsh Mistress Robert A Heinlein October 30 The Alloy of Law Brandon Sanderson November 6 Shadows of Self Brandon Sanderson November 15 The Bands of Mourning Brandon Sanderson December 3 The Martian Andy Weir December 20 Faithful and Virtuous Night Louise Glück December 23 I find it interesting to review what I gravitate towards after the fact to discover where my interests lie.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2017</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/07/books-of-2017/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/07/books-of-2017/</guid><description>The List # Book Author Completed The Hero of Ages Brandon Sanderson January 7 Real World OCaml Yaron Minsky, Anil Madhavapeddy, Jason Hickey June 28 Sane Space Tom Woods August 17 The Manager’s Path Camille Fournier November 2 Game Programming Patterns Robert Nystrom November 30 Ready Player One Ernest Cline December 10 Business Adventures John Brooks December 28</description></item><item><title>A Year Without Twitter</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/03/a-year-without-twitter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/03/a-year-without-twitter/</guid><description>Two days ago I have been off of Twitter for a year. Life has been really good without it, but I also miss everyone in the React community whose ongoing relationship was primarily based around communication on Twitter.
So I ask&amp;hellip;do I come back? Or do I carry on with my life which has been really beautiful without the world-always-burning-down ethos of Twitter.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2016</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/12/28/books-of-2016/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/12/28/books-of-2016/</guid><description>Welp, it appears I have fallen off the reading list since having two kids. I did manage to sneak 12 books in yet this past year, but with a bit more fiction than years past. Apparently as I’ve entered 30 I appreciate entertainment just as much (or more than) learning. :)
The List # Book Author Completed Professor Friby’s Mostly Adequate Guide to Functional Programming Dr Boolean February 2 A Farewell to Mars Brian Zahnd February 3 Earth Awakens Orson Scott Card, Aaron Johnston February 28 Leaving Orbit Margaret Lazarus March 4 Creativity, Inc Ed Catmull April 29 The Rust Book May 2 The Art of Strategy Avinash K.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2015</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/05/10/books-of-2015/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/05/10/books-of-2015/</guid><description>2016 was not “the Year of the Book” for me. Instead I moved into a new house, changed companies, and my wife and I had had our second child.
I also switched to Team Android, whilst my reading list was on my old iPhone, hence the reading list post in May.
The List Highlights I would recommend Engage the Fox, The Worthing Saga, The (Honest) Truth About Dishonesty, and The Music of the Primes for all audiences.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2014</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2015/01/23/books-of-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2015/01/23/books-of-2014/</guid><description>2014 was my year off from reading. Well, I read the Game of Thrones series. Now I sit here waiting for George R.R. Martin to finish the Winds of Winter so I can move on with my life for a month before waiting another 7 years for the 7th installation in the series. But alas, here is the list:
The List</description></item><item><title>Books of 2013</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2014/01/09/books-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2014/01/09/books-of-2013/</guid><description>After accidentally reading 42 books in 2012, I had quietly set myself the goal of reaching 52 books in 2013. With a last minute book off of Lean Pub I pulled it off with 1 minute 12 seconds to spare.
The List Highlights There are a few stand out books from this list. First and foremost, Thinking Fast and Slow by Daniel Kahneman is a great book. I am fascinated by how the human mind works and this was my grand introduction to psychology.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2012</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2013/01/16/books-of-2012/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2013/01/16/books-of-2012/</guid><description>In 2012, my voracious appetite for reading and learning had reached new heights. Without setting any direct goals for reading, I began the year consuming book upon book upon book and kept a running record of what I had read so at year’s end I could look back on it all and see what I had discovered.
I inadvertently almost averaged a book a week and ended the year with 42.</description></item></channel></rss>