<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reading list on Dustan Kasten</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/tags/reading-list/</link><description>Recent content in reading list on Dustan Kasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://iamdustan.com/tags/reading-list/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Books of 2020</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/04/books-of-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/04/books-of-2020/</guid><description>Catching up on posting my annual reading lists.
The List # Book Author Completed The Personal MBA Josh Kaufman February 9 The Last Wish Andrzej Sapkowski February 16 Making Work Visible Dominica DeGrandis February 21 Managing Humans Michael Lopp March 7 Managing Up Mary Abbajay March 14 Becoming Supernatural Dr. Joe Dispenza March 22 Leviathan Wakes James S.A.Corey April 5 Calibans War James S.A.Corey April 13 Hyperion Dan Simmons May 14 How to be an Antiracist Ibram X.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2019</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/03/books-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2021/10/03/books-of-2019/</guid><description>Catching up on posting my annual reading lists.
The List</description></item><item><title>Books of 2018</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2020/02/04/books-of-2018/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2020/02/04/books-of-2018/</guid><description>I’m posting this over a year late because I quit all forms of internet interactions. I’m not committing, but I’m thinking about writing to formulate my thoughts again so just pushing this up for posterity.
The List I find it interesting to review what I gravitate towards after the fact to discover where my interests lie. Standout books for this year that I have added to my recommended reading list are as follows:</description></item><item><title>Books of 2017</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/07/books-of-2017/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/07/books-of-2017/</guid><description>The List</description></item><item><title>A Year Without Twitter</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/03/a-year-without-twitter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2018/02/03/a-year-without-twitter/</guid><description>Two days ago I have been off of Twitter for a year. Life has been really good without it, but I also miss everyone in the React community whose ongoing relationship was primarily based around communication on Twitter.
So I ask&amp;hellip;do I come back? Or do I carry on with my life which has been really beautiful without the world-always-burning-down ethos of Twitter.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2016</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/12/28/books-of-2016/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/12/28/books-of-2016/</guid><description>Welp, it appears I have fallen off the reading list since having two kids. I did manage to sneak 12 books in yet this past year, but with a bit more fiction than years past. Apparently as I’ve entered 30 I appreciate entertainment just as much (or more than) learning. :)
The List</description></item><item><title>Books of 2015</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2016/05/10/books-of-2015/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2016/05/10/books-of-2015/</guid><description>2016 was not “the Year of the Book” for me. Instead I moved into a new house, changed companies, and my wife and I had had our second child.
I also switched to Team Android, whilst my reading list was on my old iPhone, hence the reading list post in May.
The List Highlights I would recommend Engage the Fox, The Worthing Saga, The (Honest) Truth About Dishonesty, and The Music of the Primes for all audiences.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2014</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2015/01/23/books-of-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2015/01/23/books-of-2014/</guid><description>2014 was my year off from reading. Well, I read the Game of Thrones series. Now I sit here waiting for George R.R. Martin to finish the Winds of Winter so I can move on with my life for a month before waiting another 7 years for the 7th installation in the series. But alas, here is the list:
The List</description></item><item><title>Books of 2013</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2014/01/09/books-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2014/01/09/books-of-2013/</guid><description>After accidentally reading 42 books in 2012, I had quietly set myself the goal of reaching 52 books in 2013. With a last minute book off of Lean Pub I pulled it off with 1 minute 12 seconds to spare.
The List Highlights There are a few stand out books from this list. First and foremost, Thinking Fast and Slow by Daniel Kahneman is a great book. I am fascinated by how the human mind works and this was my grand introduction to psychology.</description></item><item><title>Books of 2012</title><link>http://iamdustan.com/2013/01/16/books-of-2012/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://iamdustan.com/2013/01/16/books-of-2012/</guid><description>In 2012, my voracious appetite for reading and learning had reached new heights. Without setting any direct goals for reading, I began the year consuming book upon book upon book and kept a running record of what I had read so at year’s end I could look back on it all and see what I had discovered.
I inadvertently almost averaged a book a week and ended the year with 42.</description></item></channel></rss>